RAYMOND NWAMBUONWO SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Summary

Software Developer with a background in education and solution-focused development with MERN and JAMstack technologies. Utilizing the MERN and JAMstack technologies enables me to develop efficient, secure, and scalable full-stack web applications for an optimum web experience. As a former educator, I appreciate how programming increases my aptitude for learning and allows me to apply newfound concepts for efficient development practices.

Employment

Code Differently Software Developer Remote,USA Aug. 2020 to Current

- Improved educational operations by creating a two-phased roadmap in which; phase one
 consisted of lessons delivered via video and live demos; phase two consisted of project-based
 learning where junior developers work on real-world applications utilizing technology such as
 HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MERN, JAMstack, etc.
- Develop and design a multitude of web applications in collaboration with a fortune 500 company towards teaching 20 junior engineers full-stack technologies in preparation for work opportunities.
- Leading a team of 5 software engineer instructors in daily standup meetings in an agile environment to complete tasks in a timely and efficient manner.

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive Program

Washington, D.C. Sept. 2019 to Jan. 2020

- Project-focused intensive program with an emphasis on Mongo, Express, React, and JavaScript (MERN) technical stack.
- Collaborated with a team of over 25 software engineers and UI/UX designers on the design, implementation, testing, and documentation of client projects in an agile environment.
- Designed and developed responsive web applications using technologies such as HTML, CSS, Javascript, and React.JS.
- Developed command-line and back-end focused applications with databases utilizing technologies such as Python, Node.js, Express.js, Django, MongoDB, and SQL.
- Utilized a hands-on approach to develop real-world applications while maintaining two GitHub (GitHub & GH Enterprise) profiles with a combined commit history of 400+ contributions.

University of Maryland

Academic Advisor

Largo, Maryland Aug. 2018 to Aug. 2019

- Provided excellent customer service to a diverse student population by advising on strategic planning, SMART goals, and class enrollment.
- Managed progress of student academics with Salesforce and PeopleSoft software ensuring compliance with degree audits and transfer evaluations.

Projects

Portfolio

Developer portfolio with CRUD functionality utilizing JAMstack and Tailwind that showcases my
past and current projects, lessons, and blog posts.

I-Opener

 Photography portfolio web application with CRUD functionality built using the JAMstack, a Sanity.io Headless CMS backend, and Tailwind for styling.

T.A.S.A.B

• Meditation and Motivation web application built with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

000

 Skillset web application built using the MERN Stack that tracks skillset progress which is then stored in an internal API.

Rolodex

Command-line interface application "Rolodex" utilizing Python that stores users' contact
information within a PostgreSQL database.

Contact

- RaymondNwambuonwo@gmail.com
- RaymondNwambuonwo.com
- **4** 347.748.3900
- **♥** Washington D.C.
- in linkedin.com/in/raymondnwambuonwo
- RaymondNwambuonwo

Education

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive, Washington, DC

Certificate of Completion Software Engineering Immersive 2020

State University of New York College at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY

M.S. Higher Education & Student Affairs Administration 2018

State University of New York College at Oswego B.A. Mass Communications 2014

Skills

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT

Bootstrap

CSS HTML

JavaScript

ReactJS

Material UI

Tailwind

NextJs

BACK END DEVELOPMENT

Express

MongoDB

NPM

Python

PostgreSQL RESTful APIs

Node.JS

Mongoose

Headless CMS

Sanity.10

OTHER TECHNOLOGIES

Adobe XD

Agile Methodologies

Github

Heroku

MongoDB Atlas

Netlify

Postman

Git

JAMstack